Charles Dennis Collection
Charles Dennis Collection
1955-1964.
Dennis, Charles H.
0.5 linear ft.
Original cartoons, sketches, correspondence and published materials.
2653477
Biographical History
Charles Houston Dennis (1921- ) is an American cartoonist.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Charles Dennis Collection contains original gag cartoons for various magazines, sketches and cartoon ideas, correspondence and published material.
Arrangement of the Collection
Cartoons are arranged alphabetically by magazine title. Untitled cartoons are arranged by type in folder labeled "Miscellaneous". Correspondence is foldered in alphabetical order. Other materials are sorted and foldered separately.
Related Material
has collections of over one hundred cartoonists. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Dennis, Charles H.; Dennis the sex menace.; Art -- Cartoonists; American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Sex -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Cartoonists -- United States.; Cartoons (humorous images); Cartoonists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - Miscellaneous, B-S, 1956-1957; 1966 (Box 1)
- Comic strip cartoon ideas
  - The Fallen Flowers, drawings with typescript captions and notes (Box 1)
  - Horse opera, drawings with captions (Box 1)
- Gag cartoons
  - Affair (Box 1)
  - Blue Book magazine, 1955 (Box 1)
  - Heels 'n' Hose magazine (Box 1)
  - Industrial Finishing magazine, 1966; undated (Box 1)
  - Man's Magazine, 1963; 1964,; undated (Box 1)
  - M.R. magazine, 1960; 1965,; undated (Box 1)
  - Rogue magazine, undated (Box 1)
  - Satan magazine, undated (Box 1)
  - Unattributed (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous color sketches (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous ink sketches (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous pencil sketches (Box 1)
- Published material
  - Cartoon Gag Writing Principles and Techniques, 1955; booklet, priced at $2.95 (Box 1)
  - Dennis the Sex Menace, 1966; "Sex to Sexty" book by SRI Publishing; collection of adult cartoons (Box 1)